hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist in this
video we are going to discuss about the
business test cases which are an option
under the test cases section in Tosca
workspace
now what are these business test cases
and how are they useful
so business test cases help you to
basically give you an overview of the
end-to-end scenarios
and this end-to-end scenarios could be
made up of individual test cases that
cover different requirements or it could
also cover different releases or
different applications
so these business test cases they are
created in order to determine the order
of the test cases which needs to be
executed
and how they should be assigned
also they are used to map the
chronological and business perspective
together
so business execution lists which we
create they combine different execution
lists which have been executed in a
certain chronological order
and then they are brought together into
a single unit
so looking at those results uh we can
make different perspectives of the
complete business processes
so these are not concentrated on
specific test cases or a specific areas
of your application these are more wider
business processes so you need to
combine a lot of different test cases to
make a complete end-to-end business flow
then when you combine the results of all
the execution lists which are linked to
all these different test cases you can
give a business perspective to your uh
Management on whether this business
process is working or something is
broken within this business process and
this might include different
applications different releases
different execution runs or different
test cases let's see now how we can
create a business test case and how we
can create a business execution list how
we can link all of this together and get
an overview of the end-to-end business
process
so coming to our test cases section so
here um under the demo webshop I have
created three different test cases one
is for registering a user one is logging
a user and one is the order processing
so these are the three main
functionalities uh which I want to test
which might be part of one of my
requirements or might be part of one of
my business process so this is like an
end-to-end scenario which I want to test
uh in my application
so to create a business test case I have
created a folder called business
scenarios under which I'll be creating
my business test case so right click on
that folder and then you will find a
briefcase like sign which indicates that
you can create a business test case
using this particular option so click on
that and then this will be your business
test case so I'm going to name this
end to end
scenario
okay
and this end-to-end scenario will
contain all the different flows which is
part of this scenario so I'm going to
uh drag all of these different
test cases into this particular business
test case which is the end-to-end
scenario now keep in mind that when you
create a business test case it is only a
structural test case it is not a test
case which you can execute okay so it
only contains the reference of the test
cases which it is linked to so you can
consider it as a structure which
contains all the different test cases
which you want to create a business flow
for yourself okay
so this is a business test case now
which contains all the different test
cases which are linked to it
now we also need to create a business
execution list okay and for that uh
we'll again go to demo webshop and here
I have got the business scenarios
so here I am going to create a business
execution list okay
now again I'm going to name this as end
to end scenario
and then I'm going to link this to our
business test case okay
so I'm going to drag and drop this
business test case into this business
execution list
now uh apart from this we also need to
link the individual execution list
related to this test cases to this
business execution list okay
so uh now let's drag and drop the
individual execution list okay
and
it should be in a specific order okay
so let's see if these are in the
specific order okay so first register
then login and then order processing so
it is in the specific order which it
should be okay now the business
execution list is also only a structure
you cannot actually execute this so
there is no option to execute a business
execution list or a business test case
so now what it will do
it will uh concatenate all the results
from all these different execution lists
which you have linked and you will get
an overview of your end-to-end business
test flow of what is the result okay so
in this you can see it has already taken
all the results from the execution list
and it is showing it here so our
register user flow is working fine our
login user flow is working fine but our
order processing flow is currently
failing okay so this is the part which
is not working in the complete
end-to-end business flow and this is
what we can communicate back to the
business that this is the part which is
not working so we need to work on this
and we can fix this uh and then the
business flow would be working uh on an
end-to-end basis now this is just one
example of how you can do this
um as I said it could contain different
applications so you can drag different
test cases from different applications
or maybe if you want to get in a
business flow for a different releases
so you can drag different uh execution
lists from different release executions
which you have done earlier and then you
can provide the business a proper view
of what is the current scenario for the
end-to-end business flows okay
so this business just cases and business
execution lists are used for providing a
perspective to your complete end-to-end
business scenarios and this is how you
can create them
um and how you can link them together
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video